# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hey friends, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享
In this video, I am going to share about
# 西瓜的多种切法
Different ways to cut watermelons
# 首先我们来切第一种
The first way is to
# 将西瓜整齐地切成三厘米左右的厚片
Cut the watermelon into thick slices around 3 centimeters
# 然后用尖刀沿着瓜皮转一圈
Then use a sharp knife to follow the watermelon rind
# 这样可以把瓜肉分离
It can separate the pulp and the rind
# 最后再根据个人喜好划出方形或者菱形块即可
Last, cut into square or rhombus shape as your favor
# 第二种是直接切开西瓜分成两边
The second way is to cut the watermelon in half
# 翻过来用小刀插进去横着切一半
Turn it over and cut it horizontally by half with a small knife
# 再取出尖刀横向隔开几厘米继续切
Take out the knife and leave some spaces in between and continue to cut
# 然后继续纵向隔开几厘米
Continue to cut it horizontally
# 以同样的手法切到底部
Cut to the bottom using the same method
# 瓜背切好之后翻过来切瓜肉
Turn over to cut the pulp after finish cutting the rind
# 同样沿着瓜皮用小刀转圈
Follow the pulp with the small knife
# 这一步可以让瓜肉脱落瓜皮
This step can separate the pulp from the grind
# 然后再竖着将瓜肉切成小方块
Then place the pulp vertically and cut it into small pieces
# 同学们切记每一刀都需要切到底部
Guys remember to cut to the bottom every single time
# 最后将瓜肉倒出即可食用
Last pour out the pulp to eat
# 第三种也是将西瓜切成两边
The third way also need to cut the watermelon in half
# 西瓜扣过来之后直刀切成小方块即可
Turn over the watermelon and cut into dices
# 此方法比较适合切一些十斤以下的小西瓜
This way of cutting is more suitable for small watermelons under 10jin (5kg)
# 最后再分享一种粗暴式的切法
To share a more rough way at last
# 将对半的西瓜倒扣放平
Put half of the melon upside down on a flat surface
# 直接用西瓜刀砍掉周围的西瓜皮
Directly cut the rind with watermelon knife
# 然后横刀切掉瓜蒂
Then cut the top melon rind horizontally
# 切掉瓜蒂之后再横刀将瓜肉切成厚片
After the previous step, cut the pulp horizontally in thick layers
# 最后横竖刀将瓜肉剁成小方块即可
Finally, cut the pulp vertically
# 此法略显粗暴非专业人士请勿模仿
This way is kind of rough, don’t imitate unless professionals